Sean Coughlin

Software Engineer

Profile

I am a motivated Associate Software Engineer pursuing a Master of Computer Science with 1.5+ years of experience. As a dedicated full-stack engineer, I display expert Java, JavaScript, and React development skills while supporting applications used by millions of customers every month.

Employment History

Associate Software Engineer at Discover Financial Services

Riverwoods, IL, February 2022 — Present

- Drove the development of a new multi-factor authentication credit card application process, reducing required user inputs by 50%
- Implemented a new caching process increasing customer security for 600,000 customers a month
- Delivered standardized React components, shortening project delivery dates by one month
- Improved static content deployment processes, decreasing installation errors from 30% to 0%
- Advanced a weekly release cadence for eight microservices and resolved production errors while on call

Software Engineering Intern at Discover Financial Services

Riverwoods, IL, June 2021 — August 2021

- Engineered a comprehensive API testing, documentation, and demonstration tool for product owners using Angular, Spring Boot, and Swagger
- Delivered code across the digital payments ecosystem that resolved 50 code quality issues and updated APIs to support new software versions
- Furthered Scrum and Kanban based Agile teams by formulating user stories aligning to behavior driven development and fulfilling business requirements

Quality Assurance Intern at Zebra Technologies

Lincolnshire, IL, May 2020 — August 2020

- Generated a 57% reduction in testing time through expanding automated functional tests and accelerating the IT department's Agile transformation
- Streamlined the IT quality assurance team's on boarding process by building comprehensive documentation explaining team tools and best practices

Education

Master of Computer Science, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

August 2022 — May 2024

- GPA: 3.93 / 4.00
- Select Coursework: Cloud Computing Applications, Cloud Networking, Software Engineering, Data Visualization

Bachelor of Science Computer Science, Economics Minor, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

August 2018 — December 2021

- GPA: 3.88 / 4.00, High Honors
- Designed outreach programs on behalf of the University of Illinois for elementary and middle schools to encourage youth interest in STEM fields and excite future generations of engineers

Details

Chicago, IL

847-226-9006

coughlinscc33@gmail.com

LinkedIn

GitHub

seancoughlin.me

Skills

Java

Spring Boot

JavaScript (NodeJS, jQuery)

React

HTML/CSS

Git

SQL (MySQL, NoSQL)

Jira

AWS

OpenShift/PCF

CI/CD (Jenkins)

Cucumber

Personal Projects

Software Engineering Blog

Maintaining a software engineering writing series currently with 48 articles and 20,000+ views

Compound Interest Solver

Created an iOS app for financial calculations that was downloaded over 250 times

Swimming Stroke Detector

Built an object detector using Tensorflow and constructed a custom dataset for recognizing the four swimming strokes

Hobbies

Mountain climbing, hiking, running, weight lifting